Okay, so why did I show you array
dstructuring and the spread operator?
Well, this becomes very helpful when you
start to have data inside of other data.
So, for example, if we took an array and
we stuck it inside of an array, then it
could get harder to loop through that.
We haven't done that before, so I'm
going to demonstrate that to you real
quick. So, let's say we've got one
superhero, which is Bruce Wayne Batman,
and he caught 20 villains. And we could
create another superhero right below and
we'd maybe call this superhero 1 and
we'd say um Clark K Superman caught 11
villains. Um or what we could do is we
could put it all in an array. So I'm
going to bring in that array that um
Chad GBT helpfully created for me called
the Justice League array. This array
contains arrays inside of it. So for
example, in the Justice League, we have
this array right here which represents
one superhero. It has Clark, Kent, and
Superman and 12 representing the number
of villains he caught this month. So,
his first name, his last name, his hero
alias, and the number of villains he
caught this month. And you notice that
it's done that for each of these. So, if
I were to loop through the Justice
League array, each item in the array is
another array. And I could loop through
that array as well. In fact, what I want
to do is I want to print out their first
name and their last name and then say
alias and then their alias and then
caught this many villains this month.
So, let's start writing that code. So,
I'm going to say for
let hero of Justice League.
So, I'm saying take each item in Justice
League. What is an item in Justice
League? Well, it's this entire array
right here. And it says and store it in
hero. Which means if I go to hero in the
zero position on the first time through
the loop it'll pull out Clark and then
the next time through the loop it'll
pull out pull out Bruce, Diana, Barry,
Arthur, Hal, Victor and so on. So um
inside of this loop I'm going to alert
and then I'm going to create a formatted
string. You could do concatenation. I
prefer formatted strings. Um, so I'm
going to say dollar curly brace um, hero
at the zero position space dollar curly
brace hero at the one position
space alias
dollar sign and curly brace hero at the
two position
has caught
dollar sign curly brace hero at the
three position number of villains.
So this code right here will work. And
just to prove it, we're going to go over
here. It says Clark Kent, alias
Superman, has caught 12 villains. Bruce
Wayne, alias Batman, has caught 20
number of villains. Diana Prince, alias
Wonder Woman, has caught 15 number of
villains. And I'm going to take out
number of because that makes the message
sound silly. And I'm just going to put
it back to villains. So, this is okay
and it definitely works, but we could
use what we learned about array
destructuring um to make it a little
more readable. So, what I'm going to do
right here is I'm going to say let and
then I'm going to use my uh square
braces and I'm going to say first last
alias
and villains
and I'm going to set it equal to hero.
So, it's going to take each array out of
here, put it into hero, and then out of
hero, I'm going to say set the first my
variable called first equal to the first
position in the array, my variable
called last to the second position in
the array, my variable called alias to
the third position in the array, and my
variable called villains to the fourth
position array. Now, where I said hero
zero, I can just put first. Where I said
hero one, I can put last. Where I said
alias, or where I said hero 2, I can put
alias. And where I put hero 3 I can put
villains. So what I'm saying is so now
this becomes a little more readable
because now when I look at this alert
instead of saying oh they're pulling
things out of an array I see first last
alias alias has caught villains
villains. And now I know that they're
injecting the number of villains here
the alias of the superhero here and the
first and the last name here. And it's a
little more readable and therefore a
little more maintainable. All right. So,
we'll save this and we'll go over to our
code and we'll see that Clark Kent alias
Superman has called 12 villains. Bruce
Wayne alias Batman has called 20
villains. And I'm going to go through
just a couple more of these and you can
see that it is still working exactly the
way it was before. But now we've
dstructured our array so our code is a
little more readable and um we can go
from